Wait, hold on. The market's not seeing
any of this. Warren Buffer came out the
other day and he said that the market's
in a gambling route, right? That is the
reason why most traders actually lose
money. I realized that I was doing it
wrong. And when everything changed for
me was one day when I ran an experiment.
An experiment went something like this.
They're trying to frontrun Michael
Sailor's buy one green candle and
everything changes.
>> Can I challenge you?
>> The market can remain irrational. It's
completely overheated.
>> We're in the middle of a war. Oil ain't
flowing through the the most important
strategy in the world. Countries that
manufacture the chips that power the AI
revolution that the whole market is
[music] built on ain't getting gas and
ain't getting oil, whatever. Yeah.
>> And the market is just saying, "Hey, no,
we're good. Like, we're just going to
all highs." Come on.
>> Can I challenge that again? I'm from
Taiwan and we make chips.
>> Ron Norer joins us right now. He's the
founder of CryptoBanter. And I'm pleased
to co-host this show with
>> and we're at Consensus Miami. Good to
see you in person, Ran.
>> Good to see you, David. Good to see you,
Bunny. Nice to meet you. Welcome to the
show. We're just talking about trading
offline, but the personal lessons we've
learned. I'll share I'll start with a
personal anecdote. We all have personal
anecdotes. My audience knows me as not
some someone who's not a very good
trader. I always tell my my my friends,
look, use me as a contrarian indicator
because whatever I do, it turns out to
be the wrong thing to do. And so I I I I
talk about FOMO a lot on my show. I
always talk about not buying into FOMO
and doing, you know, using that as a
contrarian indicator. But I fall for
that. When Bitcoin was at $110,
$120,000, everyone was talking about
$200,000. I was like, "Yeah, let's do
it. Let's get in." Anyway, I'll stop
there.
>> You'll be glad to know that you're not
alone. And that that is the reason why
most traders actually lose money.
>> And that's because they're human. Um,
and all humans actually follow the same
emotion cycles. And I was I was exactly
the same as you when I started trading
crypto. I started trading crypto in
2015,
2016. And in those days, Bitcoin could
go from $300 to $1,000 and back down to
$300 in one day. And I'll never forget
that the first like big batch of Bitcoin
that I bought, I bought them at I think
$500. It went up to $1,000 and then they
got funded all the way down to $300 and
I sold them all at $300 and then 15
minutes later I bought them back for
$800. So the when I learned when I so I
realized that I was doing it wrong and
when everything changed for me was one
day when I ran an experiment and the
experiment went something like this. I
opened my normal trading account and I
opened a second account and the second
account I put a very little bit of money
in not not a lot and I took that second
account and I said whatever I feel like
doing I'm going to do the exact opposite
in this account. So when I felt like
buying in that account I sold on my big
account I bought. When I felt like
selling, I bought on that account and I
sold on my main account.
>> Literally started a hedge fund.
>> And what happened was my big account
emptied itself out and this tiny account
actually today is my my trading account.
And why? Because over time what I
realized is that every time that you
want to do something, do the opposite.
It's that simple. Because when you want
to do something, everybody else also
wants to do something. Right? So when
you're talking about buying Bitcoin,
everybody's thinking about buying
Bitcoin. when you're thinking about
you're never early. You're not early.
And so unless unless you have inside
information or whatever else and if
you're trading on sentiments and trading
on price moves, you're not early.
>> Let me just ask you one question. I know
Bonnie has a lot of follow-ups. We're
here at Consensus Miami. It's a good
turnout. It wasn't as good as last year
when you know we were doing our shows in
like in Miami in New York. It's
>> sentiment. No, I'm talking about the
sentiment here and the attendance,
>> right? It's like it's like it's it's
like 3/4 full and people aren't as
euphoric cuz that is that an indicator
for you. What do you feel?
>> Well, look at the crypto market. The
crypto market has been Let's talk about
the crypto market. We all expected a
bull market. The bull market never came.
It was a it was a very small bull market
in Bitcoin and it was a a bare market in
alts pretty much since January last
year. Then whoever else was left here
was flushed out on October 10th. If you
were retail and you were trading on
October 10th, you got flushed out. Then
since then, Bitcoin's been in that death
chop sideways and down, right? So, we've
gone down from wherever we've been. We
went down, we chopped and chopped and
chopped. There's no one left. Crypto is
not fun. On the other side of it, at the
same time, have you traded equities
lately? Like, listen, sex is good, but
have you traded equities lately?
[laughter] Because equities are have
given an there's been an incredible
incredible incredible bull run in
equities. You you take a company like
like Scandisk or you take a company like
Intel you take a company like AMD these
companies are doing 2x 3x 4x and 5x
that's why I got into crypto at the same
time crypto is not giving us anything it
doesn't have a heartbeat look at Salana
Salana was the darling of the of the
last one and a half bull runs right it's
at $85 and it's a stable coin now
bitcoin's gone from 60 to today 8182 and
salana is still at $85 $5. It just shows
that the life has been taken out of the
crypto market right now. And to be
honest, I'm quite surprised that it's
this full and I'm quite surprised that
people spent this much money on it. Um,
but but I think we have been through a
cleansing in the crypto market.
>> Bottom line, this is not a buy indicator
for you. The fact that it's not as
euphoric as last year because whenever
and and I've done the a lot of lot of
shows in the past. I've seen you as you
know whenever it was full
>> it usually is followed by a bare market.
That's my experience.
>> So I I agree.
>> I I mean there is a chance that we've
bottomed.
>> Yeah.
>> I think it's uh probably higher than 50%
that we've bottomed. But there's also
the traditional Bitcoin 4-ear cycle. And
if we are in the traditional Bitcoin 4
year cycle and if you if you look at the
chart generally it goes down which is
from October 10th and it goes slightly
up up up up and then it flushes everyone
down again and now we're in the part
where it's going back up up up up.
Actually funny enough today is the
turning point because if you if you
don't mind I'll steal your chart here.
>> Yeah, please.
>> Yeah, Trading View if you guys are
watching this can you please sponsor
David for a paid subscription because
[laughter] he's not a go. Thank you.
He's he's using Yeah, he's using the
unpaid version and it's very hard to
chart on this on the unpaid version. So,
if anybody from Trading View or anyone
knows anyone at Trading View,
>> um please could you help David?
>> Cheers.
>> Otherwise, if you could just like and
subscribe and just do a GoFundMe link at
the bottom. [laughter]
>> So, I said to you today was a tra was
the turning point. This is what you call
a bare flag. And the reason why it's a
bare flag is because in as I mentioned
to you guys in a in a in a bare market,
you go down and then you go up up up up
up and you convince people that the bull
run's coming back and then you flush
them out, right? And then you go down
down down down and then you go up up up
up up up and you try and convince people
that this move from 60,000 to 80,000 was
the end of the of the bull the bare
market and we're back in a bull market
and then you flash again. That's not
typical of a a bare market, a Bitcoin
bare market. It did happen once in 2022
and this could be a fake out again, but
you know, again, if it breaks, we could
be back in some kind of bull market.
>> According to the cycle, the bare market
should end in October 2026,
>> correct?
>> And
this is happening now.
>> How do I know which one is true?
>> You don't. you have to assign
probabilities to to by looking at
different patterns, right? So the if
you're following the four-ear cycle, if
that's your your thesis,
then you would say if you're following
the four cycle, this has to be a bare
flag and at some point the bare flag has
to break down. Problem is, if on the
chart the bare flag has broken the
trend, then you got to revaluate your
thesis and say, hold on a second, is is
this cycle maybe different or is this
just a normal uh uh 4year cycle? I think
that the 4-year cycle is a very weak
thesis because it's not really based on
anything. It's based on the fact that
the Bitcoin supply halves every four
years. And
in the beginning when Bitcoin was
emitting 50 and there were only a
million coins, when you added 50 to a
million coins, that was like quite a big
addition. But now like we're emitting
like 3 whatever 3.125 or whatever that
number is and there's 20 million coins
in circulation. The impact that the hing
has really can't be that significant. So
I don't believe that I don't believe
fundamentally in the 4ear cycle. That
said it has held true. So I've got to
keep it as a as a in the back of my mind
when I'm when I'm doing when I'm
evaluating scenarios that that may be a
scenario.
I think that there's about a 50% chance
that it's going to get invalidated now.
And I think that there's actually a
reason for it. I don't think blindly
that it's going to be invalidated.
I think if it was a normal market cycle,
then I think we would have probably
carried on going down. But it's not a
normal market cycle.
Why? Two reasons. One is that the S&P
500 and the stock markets are going
through a period of exuberance, extreme
exuberance.
So much so that we're in the middle of a
war. Gas prices have doubled, tripled in
some places, right?
Which means inflation is inevitably
going to go up. Like you cannot have gas
prices at $4 uh uh a gallon or whatever
it is or whichever country you live in,
which were $2 a gallon not so long ago.
Jet fuel has also doubled, which means
that flights around the world and
transportation around the world has
effectively doubled. You cannot have
that scenario with increasing inflation
and stock markets at an all-time high
breaking through channels. Right? So
that is the chart of the the S&P 500.
And as you can see, it's been in a
channel for for quite a long time,
right? Like it's been in a channel since
I think 2000. And actually, the channel
goes very far back. But what you can see
if you look here is that we've actually
just bro you imagine if there was a
trend line over here, you would have
actually broken through that channel as
well. Okay. Now, so how is it that we're
in a period of a war, period of rising
gas prices, and the S&P 500 is just gone
into alltime highs and basically brushes
off the war?
Remember, the the war is not confined to
the US. Korea, Japan can't get enough
fuel, can't get enough gas, can't get
enough fertilizer. Uh the UAE is getting
bombed. Uh uh Qatar's main gas lines
have been bombed. Like, wait, hold on.
the market's not seeing any of this. So,
we're in a period of market exuberance.
Even Warren Buffett came out the other
day and he said that the market's in a
gambling mood, right?
When the market's in a gambling mood and
when the market gets to alltime highs,
that's very good for Bitcoin and for
risk assets that are that are sitting
very far down the curve.
Next
Next.
So that's the first thing that is
working in our favor now in Bitcoin
which could invalidate the four year
cycle that we're going through a period
of real stock market exuberance.
The second thing is we have a madman, a
good madman. His name is Michael Sailor
and he's created a product which is
called STRC Stretch
which is financial financially a
financial engineering genius. That's
what it is.
He promises to pay 11 12% yield paid
monthly to anyone who buys this product.
And so what he's done is he's created a
vehicle where people are buying giving
him money expecting to get 11 12% a year
back. You ask him where do they get the
11 half% a year back? I'm raising from
you to pay him and everyone just agrees
that that's fine. Generally that would
be a Ponzi but it's not a Ponzi because
it's actually backed by Bitcoin. So why
is that important? Because in the middle
of every month the STRC becomes what
they call XD. XD means that if you're
holding it after that date, you don't
get the dividend anymore, right? And so
whenever that happens, if you look at
the chart, it dips because here you get
the dividend, but then if you're holding
it after that date, you don't get the
dividend. Every time STRC goes above
one, he can go to the market and raise
because it's trading above par. And so
now what's happening is the market's
preempting every time STRC is going to
get back to one close to the X dividend
date. And so they're trying to frontr
run Michael Sailor's buy. So if I say to
Dave, you know that in a week or two
weeks Michael Sailor is going to raise
three three or four billion dollars and
buy Bitcoin with it. What are you going
to do? You're going to buy Bitcoin now
before he raises the money and buys
Bitcoin with it. And so the whole
market's doing that. Everyone's trying
to frontr run Sailor's trade and
therefore the price of Bitcoin is going
up and in two weeks Michael Sailor will
go and buy his three or4 billion worth
of Bitcoin. And so the cycle perpetuates
itself. And so when you put those two
factors together, I think there's a very
good chance that we've actually broken
the 4-year cycle.
>> Can I challenge you on the STRC theory?
>> Sure.
>> It started trading in July 30th, 2025th.
>> But would if that theory is true, then
Bitcoin should be going up till now. So
the first the in the the uh um the to
the coin the the share the the the
instrument was launched into the market.
It took a while for the market to
understand what this instrument actually
is. Right? People first believed it was
too good to be true. Sailor was running
around promising people a 9% yield. And
it only really uh took off a lot when
sailor went out and he said, "I'm going
to 11 12%."
Then the market doubted it and they
said, "Well, where you getting the money
from?" And he said, "By the way, I've
already got 2 years worth of of of
dividends in a cash reserve." So for two
years, I don't have to worry.
>> You got a lot of stuff you have.
>> He got a lot of stuff for that job.
>> But
>> so so so it took time for the product to
get momentum. Now, when did the product
actually get momentum? Right towards the
end. So, towards the end, which is
exactly when the war started. The war
started on the 28th of Feb. And now,
everyone's worked out the formula.
When it gets to to the last day of the
dividend, people dump it. Until then, it
basically just keeps going up and up and
up because every day you're getting
closer and closer and closer to the
dividend. So, today I think if you look
at it, it's at 99.96.
Tomorrow, when you look at it, it'll be
at 99.97. The next day, 99.98. 90.99.
At one, he can go to the market. He can
sell these things at $1, which is par
value. Raise money at par value.
Whatever money he gets, he just buys
more Bitcoin. As he buys more Bitcoin,
the price goes up. As the price goes up,
he becomes more convinced or the market
becomes more convinced that he can pay
back the dividend. And then you get this
self-perpetuating cycle. So
that's that's why I think he may have
single-handedly saved the Bitcoin bare
market or traded us out of of the
Bitcoin bare market
>> and also changed four year cycle.
>> Yeah.
>> Because you have an unnatural buyer in
the market because he's created this new
instrument that is it's an infinite
glitch. He just keeps printing more
money to buy more Bitcoin.
>> Doesn't that also completely invalidate
the reason to buy Bitcoin, which is that
it's decentralized.
>> Well,
no, I don't. Although I don't like the
fact that one party has so much Bitcoin.
And there's only one reason why I don't
like it.
>> I mean, you're basically for the last 10
minutes explain why one party is moving
the price.
>> So, what he owns today 800,000 Bitcoin.
>> Yeah.
>> 800,000 Bitcoin is 4% of the Bitcoin
supply ever. If he carries on buying
like this, safe to say that he could own
5%, maybe 6% of the total Bitcoin
supply. On the one hand, that's a very
unhealthy market structure where one
participant owns five or 6% of the
Bitcoin supply. No matter how many
Bitcoin you have, you can't change the
market structure of Bitcoin because the
coins don't vote. It's not like a
company where the more equity you have,
the more vote you have. The coins don't
vote. The only participant in the market
structure in Bitcoin that votes are the
miners, right? And the miners vote where
the money is. So the miners are a bunch
of people that own computers and they
just want to produce Bitcoin at the
highest price possible, right? And
whether Sailor owns 5%, 6% or even 100%
of the Bitcoin supply, he can't vote
against
it. It's not a voting share. So it's
still as decentralized as it was before.
When they talk about decentralization,
it means
which entity owns uh which entity owns
the most mining and can the miners be
coerced into changing the blocks and
they can't.
>> How does this impact the rest of the
crypto market?
>> So if if you assume Bitcoin dominance is
going to hold, this should have an
impact on prices for other altcoins.
>> So right through this market spike of
Bitcoin, the old coins haven't moved.
Ethereum is at 2,300. Salana remains at
remains at $85. There have been
selective small altcoins that have
moved. Zcash has moved from $260 to
today $430. Hyperlids moved from 28, $29
to $43, $44. Smaller altcoins have
actually moved. I think what the
market's saying is we don't trust this.
I think like a normal cycle, you know,
there's the market cycle of crypto which
goes Bitcoin, ETH, large cap alts, small
cap alts. Let's first get confidence
that this run is real by letting Bitcoin
break the bare flag. Once that's
happened, I expect to see dominance
falling off a cliff. Right now, I think
dominance is at 60% or 60.5%. We can
quickly have a look at your
>> Yeah. btc.com
>> unpaid version of Trading View. Um,
[laughter]
>> that's the theme throughout this
episode.
>> That's That's my That's my title, by the
way. Trading View sponsor. So 61.31. So
look look at the look at the the the
yeah on this uh unpaid version of thing.
Just look at the the BDC dominance chart
up at 61.31.
This is a very good sign by the way.
This is a very very very good sign. Why?
Because if you go back historically
and you look at every time you have a
green big candle spike in Bitcoin over
here, every single time that's caused an
old coin run afters. So you almost want
to think about it like a a diver getting
into a swimming pool.
>> Yeah.
>> And the Bitcoin dominance chart going on
here.
>> And then so that's pretty much what what
this looks like.
>> Um I'll let Fonnie answer the next
question. I'm going to overlay this with
the NASDAQ. Yeah.
>> So a lot of people treat altcoins like
the tech stocks, but now the tech stocks
are trading like altcoins. If you're a
trader, you don't really care about the
underlying asset that you're trading.
Why don't you even trade crypto?
>> So, right now you don't. Right now,
crypto is not a trader market. It's been
there's been no volatility. Um, also
traders are generally unsophisticated,
which means that they make money on
longs and not on shorts. So, good
traders can make money on longs and
shorts. Most traders are making money on
longs. The majority of traders are
making money on longs. This is not a
traders market, which is why crypto
exchanges have pivoted to allowing
people to trade tokenized stocks. So,
actually, I had dinner with a friend of
mine who runs an exchange last night,
and he said, you know, we're making so
much money on the tokenized stocks that
the crypto doesn't even matter anymore.
So, right now, it's not a trader market.
Right now, it's a value market for
long-term investors. If you truly
believe in the technology, you truly
believe in Ethereum and tokenized assets
or Salana and whatever gets built on
Salana, Salana $80 is a gift. Can it go
down to 65? Maybe. But can can it go up
to a,000 also? Maybe. So for me, the
risk return now just makes sense to buy
long-term. Would I be trading the crypto
market? No. Impossible. The moves just
aren't big enough at the moment.
>> My question here is, okay, Ethereum is
useful. Salana is useful, but that
doesn't translate into a higher price
for these assets.
>> In a bare market where there's no
interest and no velocity in trading, I
agree with you. In crypto, we have a
saying and the saying is one green
candle and everything changes. So, you
get one green candle and Bitcoin goes
from 80,000 to 100,000. And that that's
happened every single bare market. Once
that happens, all the interest flies
back in and then it's almost like the
casino is open for business again. Why?
Because you know those stocks that you
spoke about, problem is that they're not
open 24 hours. And the dopamine addicts,
the traders want to trade things 24
hours, right? And you know those stocks
that you spoke about, well, that's a
really big market and it's quite uh
liquid and it's really hard to move a
big market. But when a illquid market
starts moving, you know the 100 and 200%
that you're getting in 3 months and 4
months in in a stock, well, you're
getting in 24 hours in some coins. And
so that's when the whole cycle
perpetuates itself. So I think right now
it's not a trader market. It's a value
investors market. If you've got some
patience, you buy now. We started off
this interview saying, uh, David keeps
buying when when when we're [snorts] in
peak hype.
Look, I've seen a lot of bull markets
and I can tell you the stock market is
overheated.
>> Can it remain overheated for another six
months? Yes.
>> Based on what?
>> You think I mean the market can remain
irrational? It's completely overheated.
Based on what? Based on how quickly
people are making money in the markets
based on the fact that the market
doesn't go down for any reason.
There's no there's nothing in in the
market that that can bring the market
down. Look, again, I say I don't know if
you've realized or not, but we're in the
middle of a war. Oil ain't flowing
through the the most important trade in
the world. Countries that manufacture
the chips that that power the AI
revolution that the whole market is
built on ain't getting gas and ain't
getting oil or whatever.
>> Yeah.
>> And the market is just saying, "Hey, no,
we're we're good. Like, we're just going
into alltime highs. Come on." The
market's completely completely rational
at the moment.
>> Can I challenge that again?
>> Sure.
>> Because I'm from Taiwan and we make
chips. So what happens is I think energy
there is this worry of energy not being
enough. But actually the war is not
really affecting
Taiwan or countries you mentioned Japan,
Korea
actually on ground. First of all, there
are shortages. Second of all, even if
there are no shortages, the prices have
doubled and quadrupled, which means that
the price per AI credit, let's just call
it simplified, is eventually going to
start going up. And that wasn't factored
into all the calculations when the P
when the P multiples were calculated in
this war has caused a lot of disruptions
and the markets are at all-time highs.
>> That I agree with you, but we don't know
if it's going to 2, 3x from here. And
you know what is overheated?
>> Yeah, it I I said it can it I'm still in
the markets because because they because
they can carry on being they can carry
on going up irrationally for a long
time. But
history of market cycles has taught me
that when a market cycle gets heated,
then it's time to you should maybe take
a few chips off a table. Most investors
don't do that. Most investors have got
FOMO now and they're looking to deploy
more money in cuz they're scared they're
going to miss it. How do I know this? I
woke up this morning. I saw uh Intel up
another 12% today. And I was like,
should I put some money into Intel? And
then I thought about that second account
of mine and I said, now's the time to
start shorting Intel. So, let's let's
look at the Intel price.
>> So, you shorted Intel?
>> I didn't short it. I should. I'm not
going to because I just don't have the
time and the effort to monitor short.
And I'll explain to you why. account.
That's just cash.
>> So, right now the price of in Yeah, look
at that. Look at that chart. I mean,
that's completely normal, right? Like
that's like completely normal. Nothing
wrong with that chart.
>> We call that AI boom.
>> You call it AI boom? Okay, great. It's
at 108. Now, I'm willing to take you a
bet that at some stage in the next 3,
four, five, 6 months, you will be able
to buy this back much cheaper.
>> I mean, it was okay. Just in the EIA
boom. I mean, the AI boom was all
throughout here. was losing to AMD and
Nvidia. I I just I mean, help us explain
this just as soon as you have this chart
up.
>> You see where it started turning there?
The Trump administration bought a big
chunk of Intel at that point,
>> right? So, it's not Okay. Yeah. I mean,
>> so I'm just saying I'm just saying look,
the market can continue to go up for
another 6 months, 12 months, but market
cycles means that at some point the
exuberance is going to die. There's no
exuberance in crypto right now or
there's very little exuberance and
excitement in crypto right now. So a
value investor should be looking where
there's where there's
less exuberance.
>> Let's come back to the markets in a few
minutes. I have something I want to show
you. This just came in from Coinb's
Twitter. Uh breaking hyperlquid now
trades more gold, oil, and silver than
crypto. The platform is processing more
volume in tokenized commodities than
digital assets. The 24/7 advantage,
which you've just talked about, is
pulling volume from traditional
exchanges. Can you comment on this?
>> That's exactly what I told you when we
were sitting here. I said the crypto
exchanges are having the time of their
lives because they've managed to
tokenize these assets that traditionally
trade on these highly regulated, highly
KYCed exchanges which are closed after
certain hours. And to be honest, we've
been trading oil on Hyperlquid right
through the weekends. Every time Trump
drops a bomb or negotiates or whatever
it does, we've been trading oil while
the oil markets have been closed. And
so, I mean, that's why I said
Hyperilquid's probably a great a great
one.
There's this chart
of uh new YouTube viewers that watches
English YouTube channels uh on crypto
and it was 4 million per day in 2021 and
it's about half a million per day today.
It hasn't been going up for 5 years.
>> Yeah.
>> What? In 2021, in 2021, a lot of damage
was done to retail investors who came to
crypto. I don't know if you remember,
but we had a very big bull market and it
dragged in a lot of retail money and
then we had the collapse of the
ecosystem around a coin called Luna. I
don't know if you remember Terra Luna.
And that wiped out retail investors.
Literally, people lo I mean, I lost I
took the biggest loss I've ever taken. I
think we did a show not long after that.
Um and a lot of other retail investors
lost a lot of money and kind of like got
really badly burnt by crypto and they
came back some of them came back in
certain spirits but after you know and
those that did got flushed out in
October 10th and so right now as I say
the retail interest for crypto is at an
all-time low. The institutional interest
is at an all-time high.
>> That is
>> what does that how does that translate
to prices?
So, as you've probably seen, the IBIT uh
ETF or the Bitcoin ETF has been one of
the mo if I think the most successful in
history. Um uh the the Ethereum ones are
are on a on a relative basis when you
take the market cap of Bitcoin divided
by the total amount that the Bitcoin
ETFs have bought. You take the market
cap of ETH divided by the total amount
that that the ETH thing, uh ETH is not
very far behind Bitcoin on a relative
basis.
um the digital asset treasury companies.
So Tom Lee with Bitmine,
um Michael Sailor with uh um uh Micro
Strategy, um they they've been buying,
but there's no in order to get the
velocity, you need the retail investor.
If you want to get the
stocks are about attention and velocity
or trading is about attention and
velocity. If the reason why why the big
stocks do well is because all the
attention and all the velocity is around
those stocks. More options, more
derivatives, more everything else trades
around those those stocks. Right now in
crypto, there's no re there's no
velocity. It's one-time buying, slow
buying. You need velocity. You need
energy around a stock. And that's what
we don't have at the moment. We'll get
it after one green candle. So the value
investor is buying here or maybe even
lower and then selling into the period
of max velocity which is again why I
think that at some point beware because
the stock market's going to do something
at some point.
>> Let's step away from crypto for a
minute.
>> I I love reading your ex account and
your post. They basically write my
script for me. Um this came in as the
audience knows Spirit Airlines shut down
over the weekend. He had a lot of saying
about this. Jed fuel spiked. They
weren't able to close a deal with the
Trump administration. I mean, Spirit has
been going through financial troubles
for quite some time. This was a nail in
the coffin. Elizabeth Warren had a lot
to say about this. And then you said,
"Congratulations, Elizabeth Warren
literally sent Spirit Airlines into
liquidation waiting." But what did
Elizabeth Warren after this? [laughter]
What it should be?
>> I mean I mean the the narrative was at
the time that there was a deal on the
table. She was she was very vocal and
she wrote lots of letters around
blocking the deal that was on the table
to potentially rescue this airline.
Right. And as a result of not being
rescued and they had a jetp a salvage
package
>> for Spirit eventually
it was it was it was a DOJ thing and it
was Pete Buddy
you know how to pronounce his name but I
do. Um and eventually the the deal never
went through.
>> Sure.
>> I mean that's it. That's the long and
the short of it.
>> But why should there be a deal in the
first place? I thought you were a free
markets guy themselves. Exactly. Let the
market sort themselves out. Don't block
them in the courts. Don't say that that
it's anti-competitive and that's what
happened. There was a deal. Both parties
agreed to the deal and then the DOJ and
and pressure from from the politicians
made the made it so there was no deal.
>> But should the governments even make a
deal to begin with?
>> But the government wasn't making the
deal. They they blocked the deal.
>> Okay.
>> There was a deal between JetBlue and
Spirit. JetBlue was going to rescue
Spirit. They were going to take all the
jobs. and the and when it happened the
DOJ launched an investigation and
launched a court case and under pressure
the deal fell apart and so even though
there was a willing buyer and a willing
seller and that's what I mean the
government should step in
>> shouldn't
>> no but that's that's the other argument
they should step in to prevent
>> large conglomerates and large uh cartels
from forming this is an anti-competitive
practice right
>> is that what you believe
>> not that I'm I'm just doing the opposite
of whatever experiment I was trying to
say I mean if I try to start a debate
here.
>> Yeah. Then you're sitting more left and
I'm sitting a little bit more right on
this fence. Um
>> I think that
>> in an ideal world, sorry. In an ideal
world, the government shouldn't get
involved. But that's not really what
happens in in in the real world. You do
need to protect against competitive
practices.
>> But here's one of the consequences.
There was a deal on the table to save an
airline. Now the airlines's gone. 18,000
jobs or whatever are gone. Who's going
to benefit from this? The airlines that
are currently existing, right? Cuz no
new airline is going to come up and try
and launch now with gas prices where
they are. So, who's going to benefit?
The same monopolistic
uh airlines that uh that that that would
have done the deal in the first place.
Look, this is a long discussion. It's
about, you know, whether you're sitting
more left and more right. I sit very far
right. I'm an extreme capitalist. I'm an
entrepreneur. Um, and I believe that
government should stay out of out of
commerce. Uh, unless it's really,
really, really warranted.
>> I, uh, well, last comment, okay, this is
not a left or right thing, but, um, in
Canada, if you know where I'm from,
>> very lift,
>> we have Yeah. And and
>> very, I I love a lot of things about
Canada. I hate this part. There's a few
oligopies that control everything.
Telecoms,
>> uh, comm transportation. It's probably
one of the most anti-competitive G7
countries in the world. And it's just
like everything
>> everything is slow, bureaucratic, and
the prices are uncompetitive because
there's no competition.
>> Correct.
>> And
maybe we should stop that from
happening. Maybe there should be fewer
of these larger mergers. I I just
playing devil's advocate here. What do
you think? Because eventually, if the if
these things keep happening, we're going
to end up like Canada. If you look at
the history of Canada, Canada is
traditionally a very leftist society
with a lot of rules and a lot of uh
bureaucracy
>> to get something done in Canada is very
hard.
>> Um and
>> if you take the opposite which is for
example Dubai, right? Look at Dubai.
Dubai is made for entrepreneurs. They
try and eliminate as many rules as they
can and they try and create as much
competition as they can. And that's why
they've managed to do what they've done
in in uh in that number in that amount
of time. Canada
to an extent the United States to the
the EU
make it is very difficult for people to
set up businesses and take and start
competing. Right? Give an example. I
lived in New York for a while and I
tried to operate in New York to try and
you know build certain businesses and
everywhere you go you need a permit and
a license and another permit another
license. Okay. Now we eventually moved
our operations to Dubai. We didn't need
any permits. We didn't need any
licenses. In fact, the government help
the government helped us.
>> Yeah,
>> that's the difference.
>> That's the difference. So again, I do
think it sits, you know, where you sit.
I think Canada is very left. And I think
you need to be more right. If you want
to be if you want to be faster growing
today, then you need to be more right.
And that's why I think again Dubai has
its flaws but it should be a case study
around um what can be achieved if you
change the laws into aids. In other
words to aid people to actually do what
they need to get done.
>> Places like Singapore, Dubai or even
China, they move very fast because of
the system. But I cannot imagine places
like Canada to go to that extreme or
even close to that.
>> This is this is my fake. I may get real
on this, but I think Canada has become
more socialist in China.
>> I agree. I wasn't going to say it
because I think the word socialist is
quite a strong word, but I think it's uh
you know, you go so far left that
eventually look and you become
socialist. I'll ask you a question.
as a Canadian, how or where do you think
Canada can win globally
>> needs more foreign direct investment,
which they're not going to get by doing
what they're doing now,
which is to add bureaucracy to every
single layer. In BC right now, you pro I
don't know if you're aware of this, but
in BC right now where I live,
>> they're undergoing probably the most
historic private property crisis in the
entire country where half the half the
country half the country and to extend
to 80% of the provin half the country is
in a private property battle between the
provincial government and
>> bureaucracy,
>> the Aboriginal native tribes. There's a
land claim. We don't know who owns the
land anymore. So direct investment is
not going to come. We don't know if this
piece of land belongs to first natives
or private property or crown land.
Everyone's fighting and amongst
themselves the first native tribes are
fighting for control over land. So
direct investment is gone.
>> Countries, one thing I've learned about
countries is countries have a very long
cycle of up and a very long cycle of
down.
>> Yeah.
>> So if you think about like
I want to maybe use the US, but maybe
the US is a bad example cuz Trump
actually turned it. But if you go back
to, you know, the US went on a long
cycle like this and if you if we carried
on with the Gary Gensler and Joe Biden
and and and Kla Harris, if if they got
another four years, I would say at that
point, the US would have become
uncompetitive, right? So countries go up
for a long time and then as they go up
and they get bigger, they become more
bureaucratic and then as a result of
that, they start to go down and down and
down and down and down. And I think to
be honest, I think Canada's on the down
and you take countries again I use Dubai
um and certain other countries but th
those countries because they lack
bureaucracy and they lack all these
crazy rules that are designed to protect
the incumbents
>> they are now slabbing.
>> My final question I'll pass. So what is
the next casualty from higher jet fuel
prices? Not just jet jet, sorry, not jet
jet fuel. Higher oil and higher fuel
prices overall. We saw the JetBlue and
Spirit Airlines merger fail. Spirit
Airlines fail. What's next?
>> The next casualty is going to be Donald
Trump. And I think why? Because I think
if he doesn't get this under control
really quickly, then he's going to lose
the House and the Senate in the in the
midterms. And then I think that then he
becomes a casualty, right? Then he could
be I mean at the extreme he could be
impeached. I don't think he'll get
there, but at the extreme he could be
impeached. If he doesn't sort out this
war now and inflation doesn't cuz
inflation data is 3 months delayed.
>> Yeah.
>> The oil prices from today are going to
be reflected in the inflation numbers up
until 3 months from now. Right. Which
means that today we're in May, June,
July, August. Remember the midterms are
in November which means that you can't
have inflation drop on the day of the
midterms. You want it to drop 3 4 months
before. Of course, people can say, "Wow,
look, inflation's coming down. We're all
happy. Things are getting cheaper."
Every day that goes by now, he's risking
the midterm elections. And so, I think
the next casualty is actually going to
be if he doesn't fix this war and fix
this war now and get the oil price down
now, then America becomes the casualty
because then they've got, you know, they
got to they got to split. I I don't know
if it gets split or if the if the
Democrats win both, but it just becomes
a much tougher place to make decisions.
And we know that indecision can destroy
countries, can destroy companies, can
slow things down.
>> Trump is visiting China in about 10
days.
What do you think? If you were in the
room, what do you think they'd talk
about?
>> I don't know. When I say I don't know,
it's such a tricky one because
the chi the I don't know what the
Chinese agenda is. I don't know enough
to know the Chinese agenda. Where is
now?
>> I don't know. I mean, I don't know
because I think that's way above my pay
grade. I'll be honest. I'd love to know,
but they playing a game of 70 chess that
we can't even imagine.
I mean, I'm sure they want to do trade
deals and they want to, you know, I'll
give you this and you give us that, but
it's much deeper than that.
>> But I I guess what I'm trying to ask is
how does that affect the world? So right
now there is the USD
countries and the Lemingb like the
Chinese countries where a lot of them
are in Africa. You know China is helping
a lot of African countries build their
infrastructure and stuff.
How do you see this playing out in 10
years? Let's say
>> I think um I think China becomes a much
stronger superpower at some point. I
hate saying it, but I I think it's I
think that's the case. And the reason
why I believe that that's happening is
because if you look at how long it takes
the US to get a decision about anything,
right? It has to be the Democrats and
Republicans and have to agree and have
to China. They just decide they're going
to do something and it's done. Because
if if it's not because that's just the
way it works, right?
Democracy has a lot of benefits, but
speed is not one of the benefits of
democracy. And that's why like again,
let's go back to Dubai. The reason why
Dubai works is because they don't have
to to to discuss every decision. It just
happens. The reason why China is doing
that is because they don't have to
discuss what I think is going to happen
out of that specific visit. I think
Trump's going to come out and say we are
good friends. We are we've done a good
deal and everything's amazing and we're
good friends and I think it's just going
to be a show a show for the rest of the
world. I don't think that I think that
for now, for the foreseeable future, the
US and China remain uh frenemies.
You know, they they they'll they remain
best friendmies where they smile on the
inside, but everyone's got their own
agenda and you don't mess with my agenda
and I don't mess with your agenda. I
even think like the US attack on Iran
was, you know, indirectly a blow to
China. But one of I'm sure that one of
the reasons why it happened was because
someone said, you know, if we do this,
we could probably weaken China a little
bit. So, you know, so
yeah, so I believe that they're going to
be friendnemies and they're just going
to remain friendnemies for a long time.
Calculated friends and calculated
enemies.
>> There's Well, there's a rumor that Trump
might add an additional tariff on China
if they continue to give Iran weapons.
Maybe that could be part of the talks
next week. Stop giving Iran weapons and
we'll lower the tariffs on you. I think
that he's going to talk to China about
helping end this war because no one's
winning. No one's winning here. And
China China's not gaining either.
>> Russia's winning.
>> Russia Russia's getting a lot more oil
sales.
>> Russia is getting a lot more oil. Yes.
>> Well, some of the oil has been
unsanctioned now, which is which is
amazing. China's watching the Iran war.
They're watching everything else. And I
think they know that if they wanted to
disrupt the world,
>> yeah,
>> they I mean it's just a little blockade.
Like we'll just do a little blockade
outside Taiwan. You want to blockade the
straight of our moves? will just
blockade outside Taiwan.
>> Yeah.
>> Now, let's have a discussion.
>> Fair enough. Yeah.
>> Back to your point, I watched this
documentary on TSMC and someone was
talking about how it is impossible to
uh build a TSMC
in US or any other country because in
Taiwan they do 24-hour shift. So, for
example, there's a earthquake and it's
1:00 a.m. engineers actually leave their
wives and their kids and they go
straight back to the factory just to
save the chips. That will never happen
here.
>> Can you imagine they did that in Canada?
Can you imagine what the unions would
do? What do you mean they're working
more than 4 hours a day? [laughter]
That's a